AITA for skipping
my friend's daughter’s
1st birthday and
charging her for
the "gift" after
she forgot to
tell me the
time changed? I’m
feeling pretty heated
right now and
need some perspective.
My friend’s daughter
is turning one
today. A few
weeks ago, my
friend asked if
I could make
truffles for the
party. I agreed,
and she mentioned
she would reimburse
me for the
ingredients. However, because
truffles are expensive
to make and
incredibly labor-intensive, I
decided I would
just gift them
as the birthday
present instead of
asking for money.
I spent all
day yesterday in
the kitchen making
these. I had
to wake up
super early this
morning to finish
the final touches
and get ready
for the 9
AM start time
listed on the
invitation. I showed
up at 9
AM sharp, truffles
in hand, and
the place was
empty. I double-checked
the invite and
it definitely said
9 AM. I
called my friend,
and she casually
told me that
the time had
been changed to
the afternoon. She
admitted she "forgot"
to tell me,
and apparently, I
was the only
guest who wasn't
notified. After working
so hard yesterday
and sacrificing my
Saturday morning sleep,
I was (and
am) pissed. I
havent told her
if ai can
make it in
the afternoon yet
WIBTA if I
charge her the
full amount for
the ingredients and
my time since
I might no
longer be attending
and these were
meant to be
the “gift” or
refuse to go
to the afternoon
session because I’ve
already wasted my
morning and now
I "have other
plans" (which is
mostly just being
too annoyed to
celebrate)? EDIT: I
did not tell
her I would
gift her the
truffles, I had
just decided that
myself EDIT: A
lot of people
are asking for
more context so
here it goes.
We moved to
a new city
last year so
I’ve been trying
hard to make
new friends and
I’ve been hanging
out with this
friend and some
of her friends,
but I’m not
“in” their little
group yet. I’m
a very helpful
person in general
and have a
lot of party
planning experience, so
I actually helped
her decide many
aspects of the
party, like how
much food, what
types of food,
how many drinks,
etc. We were
exchanging info back
and forth about
this party constantly
and I even
lent her a
bunch of my
own decor stuff
to use for
the cake table.
Also, she specifically
chose 9 am
because that’s when
her daughter is
most alert and
happiest, so this
was supposed to
be a brunch
type birthday party.
Given how much
we talked about
the details and
the fact that
she has my
decor, I really
don't feel like
this was an
easy thing to
"forget."